Finding Aid for the Barbara and Willard Morgan photographs and papers LSC.2278
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 3: Barbara Morgan professional materials, 1929-2000s
  - Subseries 3.2: "Permanence" files, 1944-1979
    - Photograph notes - processing, undated (Box 47, Folder 13)
      Includes Barbara Morgan's photo directions for printing Letter to the World (Kick) and Ekstasis (Graham), Rock Daniel (Primus), and Passagaglia (Humprhey). Also includes notes on a solution for processing by Steichen.
      See also Box 47, f. 1 for a letter and notes from Ansel Adams to Barbara Morgan with Adams' specifications for processing and printing.
    - Spotting/jotting, 1975 (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - Technical - photography - platinum - Candelario, 1944 (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - Vestal, David, 1977 (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 3.3: Published photographs, 1930s-2000s
    Copies of printed material in which Barbara Morgan's photographs appeared, including books, magazines, and various ephemera, such as theater playbills.
    - Martha Graham photographs, 1930s-2000s (Box 48, Box 49, Box 50, Box 436, Box 440, Box 196)
    - Other dance photographs, 1930s-2000s (Box 50, Box 151)
    - Other photographs, 1930s-2000s (Box 152, Box 153)
    - Unknown photographs, 1930s-2000s
      - Photographic magazines, including Camera and Darkroom, Popular Photography, Life, National Geographic, Art On Paper, and ARTnews, (2 folders) (Box 209)
- Series 4: Barbara Morgan photographic projects, 1930s-2008; The photographic materials included in this series consist of photographic prints, contact sheets and prints, and negatives. The photographic prints range from small (up to 8 x 10 format), to medium (up to 16 x 20 format), to large (over 16 x 20 format).
  CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIO MATERIALS: Audio materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email AskLSC@library.ucla.edu.
  This series contains material generated from Barbara Morgan's major photography projects, including the Bennington College Festival of Modern Dance, the books Martha Graham: Sixteen Dances in Photographs, Summer's Children, Presitini's Art in Wood, and others, as well as numerous smaller projects, such as photography for colleges and other schools. Materials for her project and book ideas are also included.
  See also Subseries 19.5 for materials related to the Morgan family project, Growing Americans (Chicken Movie.)
  - Subseries 4.1: Bennington College Festival of Modern Dance, 1938-1982; 1938-1939
    This subseries contains correspondence and other documentation related to Barbara Morgan's photographs of the Bennington College Festival of Modern Dance in 1938. It also includes a range of photographic prints, contact sheets and prints, and negatives.
    - Correspondence, 1938-1970 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence re Morgan photographs of Bennington Festival, 1938-1969 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Dancers and dances performed at Bennington (list) with Morgan photograph numbers (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Oral history: Barbara Morgan interviewed by Theresa Bowers, 1982 (Box 51, Folder 3)
      Includes transcript, publicity and ephemera related to the interview.
    - Publicity, 1938-1939 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Storyboards, circa 1938 (Box 447, Folders 4-5)
    - Photographic prints (large), undated (Box 448, Folder 1)
      Box 448, Folder 1 contains 8 x 10 prints of Graham dancers matted on a large foamcore board.
    - Photographic prints (medium), 1938
      - Martha Graham: with Erick Hawkins at Bennington (non-dance on grass, sky background), Graham solo at Sarah Lawrence, and in Deep Song and Ekstasis (torso); Hawkins in American Document; Graham and Group in American Provincials, Deaths and Entrances, 1935-1938, undated.; Black and white prints, 8 x 10 and larger, printed on 11 x 14 photographic paper, unmounted. 20 folders (20 prints) (Box 336)
      - Experimental double exposure dance prints, 1935-1938, undated. (Box 336)
      - Graham in Deaths and Entrances, and Tamiris-Nagrin in When the Saints Go Marching In, 1935-1938, undated.; 8 x 10 prints, mounted (Box 336)
      - [Martha Graham and Erick Hawkins, outdoors, Bennington College], 1938; 11 x 14 format prints. (Box 336)
      - Louis Horst with Daschund and Dancer, Bennington College. (Faces of Modern Dance 10), 1938, printed 1973.; Signed. Gelatin silver print. Print is trimmed to 7-1/2 x 9-1/4 in., mounted on a board 11 x 12-7/8, then matted to 14 x 18 in. (Box 348)
      - Candid: Doris Humphrey, Charles Weidman and unidentified. Bennington Commons. Photograph #5030, 8 x 10 format print matted to 17 x 14 inches. (Box 348)
      - Weidman (Group), Opus 51, 1938.; Print matted to 20 x 16 in. with 5-3/4 x 8 in. mat window. Signed. (Box 371)
    - Photographic prints (small), 1938, undated
      - Dancers at Bennington in 1938 in rehearsal, backstage in costuming and make-up, casual group and with Louis Horst, 8 x 10 vintage prints. (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - Graham and Hawkins, and Graham Group (Box 51, Folders 7-8)
      - Graham and Hawkins at Bennington, 8 x 10 prints, vintage and printed later. (Box 51, Folder 9)
      - Graham and Hawkins, and Graham Group Cunningham, Bettis, Humphrey, Si Lan Chen, and Holm, 1938; 4 x 5 contact prints. (Box 51, Folder 10)
      - John Martin (dance critic), musicians, and Bennington dancers (portraits and casual) (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - John Martin, Martha Graham, Louis Horst, Frances Hawkins, Housely Stevens, Jr., Barbara Morgan, Norman and Ruth Lloyd, Doris Humphrey and Charles Weidman, 8 x 10 prints.; Also includes contact sheets of Hany Holm Group in Trend (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Cut film - negatives and contact prints, 1938, undated
      General
      For more detailed descriptions of the 4 x 5 negatives and contact prints of Martha Graham and Group and other dancers at Bennington College, see files for Negatives and Contact Prints under Subseries 9.2 Dance Photography--Martha Graham and 9.2 Dance Photography--Other Dancers.
      - Martha Graham and other dancers at Bennington College, 1938; 4 x 5 contact prints. (Box 51, Folder 10, Box 290, Box 302, Box 305, Box 433, Box 435, Box 454, Box 458, Box 462, Box 463, Box 562)
      - Martha Graham and other dancers at Bennington College, 1938; 4 x 5 negatives. (Box 434, Box 435, Box 454, Box 458, Box 462, Box 463, Box 562, Box 563)
      - Graham and Group, Graham and Hawkins, Louis Horst, and candid shots of other dancers at Bennington College, circa 1925-1938, undated; 5 x 7 and 35mm color and black and white transparencies. (Box 558)
        Includes 35mm color transparencies of Graham and Hawkins.
        Martha Graham and Group in Primitive Mysteries and other dances, Martha Graham and Erick Hawkins, Louis Horst, and candid shots of other dancers at Bennington College.
  - Subseries 4.2: Book projects, 1930s-1997
    CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIO MATERIALS: Audio materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email spec-coll@library.ucla.edu.
    This subseries contains correspondence, reviews, publicity, photographic material, and other documentation of Barbara Morgan's major photography book projects. It also includes the typescript and photographic material for an unrealized book project about Marie James, the Morgan family's cook and housekeeper.
    - Barbara Morgan (Aperture), 1964 (Box 52)
    - Barbara Morgan (Aperture - Masters of Photography Series), 1988 (Box 1)
    - Barbara Morgan (monograph), 1972-1973 (Box 52)
    - Barbara Morgan Photomontage, 1980-1981 (Box 53)
    - Martha Graham book - early model with loose photographic prints, circa 1930s, undated (Box 201, Box 241)
    - Martha Graham: Sixteen Dances In Photographs - correspondence, publicity, reviews, 1941-1947 (Box 53)
    - Martha Graham: Sixteen Dances In Photographs - revised edition, 1963-1981 (Box 53, Box 208)
    - Martha Graham: Sixteen Dances In Photographs - loose sketch, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 436)
    - Martha Graham: Sixteen Dances In Photographs - book boards, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 202, Box 203, Box 204)
    - Martha Graham: Sixteen Dances In Photographs - boards and notes, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 205, Box 206)
    - Martha Graham: Sixteen Dances In Photographs - 1968(?) 3rd edition boards & BBM notes, 1930s-1980s (Box 207, Box 208)
    - Summer's Children: A Photographic Cycle of Life at Camp - correspondence, book jackets, publicity, reviews, 1944-1991 (Box 54, Box 55, Box 440)
    - Summer's Children: A Photographic Cycle of Life at Camp - first editions, 1951 (Box 56, Box 209)
      The items consist of five hardbound first editions: two in orange cloth and three in blue cloth. One has a dust jacket, two have been inscribed by Barbara Morgan to others, and one has been inscribed by others at a book release party for Morgan.
    - Summer's Children: A Photographic Cycle of Life at Camp - photographic prints (large), circa 1930s-1950s, undated
      - Children Dancing by the Lake, 1940 (printed 1972).; 2 prints. One print is mounted on 18 x 20 in. board, and one print is matted to 18-1/4 x 22-1/2 inches. (Box 385)
    - Summer's Children: A Photographic Cycle of Life at Camp - photographic prints (medium), circa 1930s-1950s, undated
      - 11 x 14 format and smaller prints, including Girl With Recorder, and [Untitled] (10 prints). Also includes 2 mounted prints, White Horse Dancing, and Camp Singing., 1951, Undated. (Box 323, Folders 3-4, 14-23)
      - Girl Playing Recorder, 1945.; 16 x 20 format print. (Box 364, Folder 14)
    - Summer's Children: A Photographic Cycle of Life at Camp - photographic prints (small), circa 1930s-1950s (Box 55, Box 56)
    - Summer's Children: A Photographic Cycle of Life at Camp - photographic prints by Willard, circa 1930s (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Summer's Children: A Photographic Cycle of Life at Camp - New York Public Library Reading Room photographic prints, circa 1944-1948 (Box 56, Box 436, Box 341, Box 353)
    - Summer's Children: A Photographic Cycle of Life at Camp - Kodak show mounted photographic prints, 1940s-1950s (Box 210)
      Photographs mounted on thick, painted wooden circles and squares.
    - Summer's Children: A Photographic Cycle of Life at Camp - contact sheet books, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 313, Box 314)
    - Summer's Children: A Photographic Cycle of Life at Camp - photographic prints (contact prints) and negatives, 1930s-1950s; 8 x 10 format negatives: Box 56, folder 7 Contact prints, 5 x 7 format and smaller: Boxes 423, 426, 429. Negatives, 5 x 7 format and smaller: Boxes 553, 554, 560. Negatives and contact prints, 4 x 5 format and smaller: Boxes 56 folder 7, 529, 530, 531, 536, 538, 540, 556, 607, 608. (Box 56, Box 423, Box 426, Box 429, Box 529, Box 530, Box 531, Box 536, Box 538, Box 540, Box 542, Box 553, Box 554, Box 556, Box 560, Box 607, Box 608)
      Many of the Camp Treetops negatives and contact prints include Douglas and Lloyd Morgan.
      Some of the camp negatives correspond to prints in Box 430.
    - Marie James project - typescript, 1947 (Box 57)
    - Marie James project - introduction, notes, 1947 (Box 58)
    - Marie James project - table of contents, 1997 (Box 58)
    - Marie James project - photocopy of typescript, 1997 (Box 58)
    - Marie James project - obituary and personal, 1979 (Box 58)
    - Marie James project - photographic prints and negatives, circa 1947; Box 58 contains prints. Box 556 contains negatives. (Box 58, Box 556)
    - Marie James project - wire recordings, circa 1947 (Box 58)
  - Subseries 4.3: Buddhism materials, circa 1955-1976
    This subseries contains materials related to Barbara Morgan's work on Buddhism, especially on D.T. (Daisetsu Teitaro) Suzuki and the spread of Zen in the West.
    For additional portraits, see Series 9: Barbara Morgan photographic material, Subseries 9.6: People and Animals (including Strobe Series).
    - Zen Institute, 1958-1973 (Box 61, Folder 2, Box 188, Folder 8)
    - Suzuki-related correspondence, 1956-1974 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Suzuki and Alan Watts, 1957-1966 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Tibetan info, 1976 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Kalmuk Tibetan Buddhist Colony (Freewood, New Jersey) - photographic prints, circa 1955 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Misc. Tibetan, Suzuki, and others - photographic prints, circa 1955, undated (Box 61, Folders 7-8)
    - Misc. Tibetan, Suzuki, and others - contact prints, circa 1955 (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - Misc. Tibetan, Suzuki, and others - negatives, circa 1955 (Box 608)
      - Kalmuk Buddhists in Freewood Acres, New Jersey. Wesley Needham-Dilowa Hutktu-Wanjo, February 27, 1955.; Color and black and white negatives. (Box 608, Folder 19)
  - Subseries 4.4: Prestini's Art in Wood project materials, 1945-1989
    This subseries contains correspondence, publicity, photographic prints, and negatives related to Prestini's Art in Wood, a collaborative project between Barbara Morgan and the sculptor James Prestini, featuring Morgan's photographs of Prestini's wooden bowls. Copies of the finished book are also included.
    Prestini and Morgan were friends and corresponded for many years, with Prestini sending Morgan philosophical commentary about current events in addition to letters. See also Subseries 2:1: Personal Correspondence.
    - Correspondence and publicity, 1945-1989 (Box 59)
    - Dummy editions and first editions, 1950 (Box 59)
    - Photographic prints (medium), circa 1948-1950 (Box 323, Box 437)
    - Photographic prints (small), circa 1949-1950 (Box 60)
    - Negatives, circa 1950 (Box 59, Box 60, Box 545)
  - Subseries 4.5: Sarah Lawrence College photographic work, 1955-1957
    This subseries contains material related to Barbara Morgan's Sarah Lawrence College photographic work, including images for the College catalog of campus buildings, classes, students, and professors; images from a student trip to Canada; and of Martha Graham dancing on campus in 1937.
    For additional portraits of people, see Subseries 9.6: People and Animals (including Strobe Series).
    - Correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 211, Folder 8)
    - Publications, 1956-1957 (Box 211, Folder 9)
    - Photographic prints (medium) - campus life, people, and Canada trip, circa 1953-1956 (Box 338, Box 344, Box 437)
      - Prof. Joseph Campbell, Sarah Lawrence College, 1953., Print trimmed and mounted on 12 x 14 in. board. (Box 338, Folder 9)
    - Photographic prints (medium) - Martha Graham, 1937, undated; Black and white prints, 8 x 10 and larger, printed on 11 x 14 photographic paper, unmounted. 20 folders (20 prints) (Box 336)
      - Martha Graham, solo, outdoors, 1937.; 11 x 14 format prints (3 prints). (Box 336)
      - Martha Graham: with Erick Hawkins at Bennington (non-dance on grass, sky background) (Box 336)
      - Graham solo at Sarah Lawrence, and in Deep Song and Ekstasis (torso) (Box 336)
      - Hawkins in American Document (Box 336)
      - Graham and Group in American Provincials, Deaths and Entrances. (Box 336)
      - Graham: Deaths and Entrances, and Tamiris-Nagrin in When the Saints., Experimental double exposure dance prints. 8 x 10 prints, mounted. (Box 336)
    - Photographic prints (small) - campus life, people, and Canada trip, 1955-1956 (Box 211, Folders 10-15, Box 212, Folders 1-32, Box 213, Folder 1-19)
    - Photographic prints (small) - Martha Graham, 1937, undated (Box 211, Folder 7)
    - Contact sheet books, 1955-1956 (Box 213, Folder 20, Box 315)
    - Cut film - negatives and contact prints, 1937, 1955-1956
      - Fencing and other student activities, buildings, jazz musician Martin Gornley, Doris Riker, 1938-1957.; 4 x 5 negatives and contact prints (Box 435)
      - Sarah Lawrence College, undated. (Box 536)
      - Sarah Lawrence College, 1955-1957.; 4 x 5 and smaller negatives. (Box 561)
        Corresponds with contact prints in Box 435.
    - Roll film - negatives and contact sheets, circa 1955 (Box 214, Folder 1, Box 608, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 4.6: Other projects, 1936-2008
    This subseries contains documentation of other projects Morgan took on, as well as some posthumous uses of her work, including photography for other schools, various dance-related projects, dance reconstructions, and her occasional book design work, such as for the World of Albert Schweitzer and a collaboration between Morgan, Martha Graham, and William Carlos Williams for the portrait War Theme.
    - Anais Observed, Robert Snyder, 1974 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Calendar - To the Dance, 1988 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Cards and postcards--Dance, Experimental, Children, 1940s-1990s (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Clarkville School - photographic prints, 1949 (Box 216, Folders 1-2, Box 188, Folder 9)
    - Clarkville School - contact prints, 1949 (Box 216, Folder 3)
    - Conquest of Civilization - jacket photomontage, 1938 (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - Dalton School - photographic prints, circa 1941 (Box 216, Folders 4-5, Box 437, Folder 6)
    - Dalton School - image lists with digitized thumbnails, undated (Box 216, Folder 6)
    - Dalton School - "Children M+D L+D" photographic prints, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 216, Folder 7, Box 437)
    - Dalton School - contact prints and negatives, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 533, Box 541, Box 607, Folder 2)
      Box 533 also includes North Country School.
    - Dance reconstruction - Accelerated Motion, 2005 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Dance reconstruction - Brooklyn Academy of Music, 1994 (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - Dance reconstructions, 1960s-1990s (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - Deba Patnaik book - negatives and contact prints, 1930s-1940s, 1990s, undated; 1930s-1940s (Box 429, Folder 5)
    - "DP Book" (Deba Patnaik) - photographic prints and contact prints, 1930s-1940s, undated (Box 61, Folder 11, Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Edgemont High School - negatives and contact sheets, 1957 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Fresh Air Camp, Hidden Valley, and deer at Camp Anita., 35mm and 72mm negatives. (Box 607)
    - Ginn Reading Program - children's book, 1981 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Herald Tribune Fresh Air Fund - photographic prints, contact sheets, and negatives, circa 1956, 1958 (Box 216, Folder 8, Box 430, Folders 3-5, Box 437)
    - Louis Horst and the American Dance - with Ernestine Stodelle, 1964 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Other Ernestine Stodelle projects, 1990-1995 (Box 62, Folders 6-7)
    - Doris Humphrey centennial, 1995 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Phillips Exeter Academy, 1936 (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Diego Rivera, New Workers School, 1933 - photographic prints, undated (Box 216, Folder 10)
    - Smith College - correspondence and publications, 1959-1960 (Box 62, Folders 9-11)
    - Smith College - photographic prints and contact prints, 1959-1960 (Box 211, Folder 1)
    - Technique of Martha Graham, Alice Halpern, 1994 (Box 211, Folders 2-3)
    - To Lighten My House, Alastair Reid, 1953 (Box 211, Folder 4)
    - To Lighten My House, Alastair Reid - photographic prints and acetate negatives, circa 1953 (Box 211, Folder 5)
    - War Theme - William Carlos Williams and Martha Graham, 1944-2008 (Box 211, Folder 6)
    - Women's Photography Journal, 1976 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - World of Albert Schweitzer, 1954-1955 (Box 63, Folders 2-4)
    - Unidentified negatives (Barbara Morgan) (Box 607, Folders 3-4)
  - Subseries 4.7: Book and project ideas, 1930s-1970s
    This subseries includes plans for photography books or projects, and other writings and ideas for photographic work. The folder contents range from official proposals directed to publishing companies to research material and annotations. This material somewhat overlaps with Series 5: Barbara Morgan writings, Subseries 5:3: Unpublished writings.
    - Book - Child's Thoughts, 1952 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Book - City Theme, circa 1937 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Book - Edna B., undated (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Book - Modern Dance (with Charles Woodford), 1975 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Book - Papago Indians, 1952 (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Book - Signs of Manhattan, 1957 (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Book - Tibetan Mudras, 1954-1964 (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - Book - United Nations, 1954 (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - "The Book", 1960s (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - Book themes, quotes, research data, 1969 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Writing and photography ideas, 1940s-1950s (Box 65, Folders 2-7)
- Series 5: Barbara Morgan writings, 1917-1980s
  The Barbara Morgan writings series ranges from published articles to notes and annotations about art, photography, and other subjects. It also includes her draft of the unpublished photography work Dynamics of Composition, personal journals, and "Think Books," in which Morgan recorded her thoughts and philosophies about art, religion, and other subjects.
  - Subseries 5.1: Published articles, 1927-1970s
    This subseries includes drafts, notes, and final copies of Morgan's published articles on photographic philosophy and technique.
    - "Abstraction in Photography" - Encyclopedia of Photography, 1962 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - "Advancing Photography as a Fine Art" - Encyclopedia of Photography, 1962 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - "The Art of Photography", 1949 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - "The Art of Photography in Trends Today", circa 1950 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - "Aspects of Photographic Interpretation" - General Semantics Bulletin, 1965 (Box 66, Folders 5-6)
    - "Birth and Proliferation of the Photographic Image" - Aperture, 1962 (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - "Dance Photography" - Complete Photographer, Encyclopedia of Photography, U.S. Camera, 1940-1965 (Box 66, Folders 8-10)
    - "Dynamics of Composition" - Leica Manual, circa 1970s (Box 66, Folder 11)
    - "Esthetics of Photography" - Complete Photographer, Encyclopedia of Photography, 1942, 1962 (Box 66, Folders 12-13)
    - "Is Black and White Better than Color?" - Modern Photography, 1952 (Box 66, Folder 14)
    - "Juxtapositions in Photography" - Complete Photographer, Encyclopedia of Photography, 1942, 1962 (Box 66, Folders 15-16)
    - "Kinetic Design in Photography" - Aperture, 1953 (Box 66, Folder 17)
    - "The Meaning of Modernism in Art" - Artland, 1927 (Box 66, Folder 18)
    - "Modern Dance" - Popular Photography, 1945 (Box 66, Folder 19)
    - "My Creative Experience With Photomontage" - IMAGE Journal, 1971 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - "Photographer's Ego Vs An Anonymous Medium" - Spectrum Magazine, 1956 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - "Photographing Martha Graham", 1972 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - "Photographing the Dance" - Graphic Graflex, 1947 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - "Photography, The Youngest Visual Art" - Magazine of Art, 1942 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - "Photomontage" - The Complete Photographer, Encyclopedia of Photography, Miniature Camera Works, 1938-1962 (Box 67, Folders 6-8)
    - "Russell Lee, Photographer" - Retrospective Exhibition Catalog, 1965 (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - "The Scope of Action Photography" - The Complete Photographer, 1941 (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - "The Theme Show: A Contemporary Exhibition Technique" - Aperture, 1955 (Box 67, Folder 11)
    - Book review: Under the Sun by Lyons, Lebrott, Chappell - Aperture, 1961 (Box 67, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 5.2: Dynamics of Composition, 1960s-1970s
    This subseries includes drafts and notes for Morgan's unpublished book Dynamics of Composition, which she spent years compiling. It also includes photographs of Morgan at work on the project, and her organizational systems.
    - Outline, Introduction, Preface; Chapters 2-6, 1970s (Box 68)
    - Chapters 6-7, 10-13, 1970s (Box 69)
    - Chapters 14-16; notes and research materials, 1970s (Box 70)
    - Notes, format and design notes, photographic prints, 1960s-1970s (Box 71, Box 440, Folder 4)
    - Photographic prints - dance, pig family, Gerald Heard, Prestini, Barbara working, 1970s (Box 72)